<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Collegian</title>
	<atom:link href="https://fscollegian.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://fscollegian.com</link>
	<description>Fresno State&#039;s student-run newspaper</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 19:26:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Dogs in the NFL: Week 14</title>
		<link>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/dogs-in-the-nfl-week-14/</link>
					<comments>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/dogs-in-the-nfl-week-14/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[By Finnley Pendergast, Reporter]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 19:13:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Football]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Former Bulldogs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Davante Adams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[derek carr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ronnie rivers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://fscollegian.com/?p=111695</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Carr suffers injury in Saints win The New Orleans Saints kept their playoff hopes alive with a win over the New York Giants on Sunday. With the help of defensive tackle Bryan Breese, who blocked a potential game-tying field goal, the Saints held on, winning 14-11. Despite the win, the Saints may be without their...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><b>Carr suffers injury in Saints win</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The New Orleans Saints kept their playoff hopes alive with a win over the New York Giants on Sunday. With the help of defensive tackle Bryan Breese, who blocked a potential game-tying field goal, the Saints held on, winning 14-11.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite the win, the Saints may be without their starting quarterback for the rest of the year.</span></p>
<div class='infographicwidget'><div class='center'></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Saints?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Saints</a> QB Derek Carr is feared to have suffered a fracture in his left, non-throwing hand, sources tell me and <a href="https://twitter.com/TomPelissero?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@TomPelissero</a>. Another frustrating injury situation for Carr and New Orleans. <a href="https://t.co/6hHDHD3pao">pic.twitter.com/6hHDHD3pao</a></p>
<p>— Ian Rapoport (@RapSheet) <a href="https://twitter.com/RapSheet/status/1865891420587888991?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 8, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div></div><div class='clear'></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Late in the fourth quarter, Derek Carr injured his left hand when he dove to try and get a first down and hit the ground hard. Carr missed the rest of the game with former Bulldog, Jake Haener, coming in to take over. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Carr finished with 219 passing yards, adding a passing touchdown but also an interception.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Further tests revealed Carr suffered a fracture in his non-throwing hand. Carr is also in concussion protocol due to the fall. The Saints quarterback may be placed on the injured reserve with a high possibility of missing the rest of the season.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This won’t be the first time the Saints have been without their starting quarterback this year. When Carr was dealing with an oblique injury, Spencer Rattler was the starting quarterback. But with Rattler unable to lead the Saints to a win in his short stint as the starter, New Orleans may go in Haener’s direction.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fans will have to wait and see who starts when the (5-8) Saints next take on the (8-5) Washington Commanders on Sunday, Dec. 15.</span></p>
<p><b>Davante stays busy in overtime loss</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The New York Jets lost to the Miami Dolphins 32-26 on Sunday, but the offense was able to move the ball.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Davante Adams finished with nine receptions for 109 receiving yards and a receiving touchdown.</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">His longest catch went for 34 yards.</span></p>
<div class='infographicwidget'><div class='center'></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Aaron Rodgers finds Davante Adams in the end zone for the 79th (!!!) time</p>
<p>They pass Ben Roethlisberger and Antonio Brown for 4th most by any QB-WR duo in NFL history including playoffs. <a href="https://t.co/mF1dwdd1iv">pic.twitter.com/mF1dwdd1iv</a></p>
<p>— NFL on CBS (@NFLonCBS) <a href="https://twitter.com/NFLonCBS/status/1865847357226557496?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 8, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div></div><div class='clear'></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite quarterback Aaron Rodgers having one of his best performances with the Jets, the Dolphins were able to win in overtime.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The (3-10) Jets will look to keep the offense hot when they take on the (3-10) Jacksonville Jaguars on Sunday, Dec. 15.  </span></p>
<p><b>Ronnie Rivers makes clutch play in win</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Running Back Ronnie Rivers was able to come up with a key onside recovery for the Rams late in the game in their 44-42 win over the Bills.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“It feels great to be able to compete and come out with a win against a team like that,” said Rivers. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rivers has seen his playing time in the Rams backfield go down but was able to make a big play on special teams.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The (7-6) Rams will look to build off their impressive win when they play on Thursday Night Football against the (6-7) San Francisco 49ers on Dec. 12.</span></p>
<p><b>Other ‘Dogs around the league</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Defensive end Aaron Mosby recorded a tackle in the Packers’ loss to the Lions. The (9-4) Packers will next face the (8-5) Seattle Seahawks on Sunday Night Football on Dec. 15.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Defensive back Daron Bland made five total tackles, and had a pass defended in the Cowboys’ loss to the Bengals on Monday Night Football. The (5-8) Cowboys will next play the (3-10) Carolina Panthers on Sunday, Dec. 15.</span></p>
<div class='infographicwidget'><div class='center'></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">good to see ya again <a href="https://twitter.com/DaRon_Bland?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@DaRon_Bland</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/BulldogBornBulldogBred?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#BulldogBornBulldogBred</a></p>
<p>: <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/CINvsDAL?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#CINvsDAL</a> on ESPN/ABC<br />
: Stream on <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/NFLPlus?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#NFLPlus</a> &amp; ESPN+ <a href="https://t.co/ylE2eX3m62">pic.twitter.com/ylE2eX3m62</a></p>
<p>— Fresno State Football (@FresnoStateFB) <a href="https://twitter.com/FresnoStateFB/status/1866298884458176541?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 10, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div></div><div class='clear'></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Week 14 had a couple teams with former Bulldogs on bye this week including the Broncos’ Levelle Bailey and Commanders’ Mykal Walker. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/dogs-in-the-nfl-week-14/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Armenian Students Organization Has Active Fall 2024 Semester</title>
		<link>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/armenian-students-organization-has-active-fall-2024-semester/</link>
					<comments>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/armenian-students-organization-has-active-fall-2024-semester/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[By Ani Sargsyan, Staff Writer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 20:07:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ethnic Supplements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hye Sharzhoom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://fscollegian.com/?p=111690</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ani Sargsyan Staff Writer The Armenian Students Organization had a very successful semester, with four events held during the Fall 2024 semester, and one being planned for the month of December. On Friday, October 25, students gathered for the ASO Halloween Party, and students were encouraged to bring pumpkins for a painting/carving contest, as well...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Ani Sargsyan</strong></p>
<p><em>Staff Writer</em></p>
<p>The Armenian Students Organization had a very successful semester, with four events held during the Fall 2024 semester, and one being planned for the month of December.</p>
<figure id="attachment_111692" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-111692" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-small wp-image-111692" src="https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/pg.-7-ASO-Halloween-November-final-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/pg.-7-ASO-Halloween-November-final-300x225.jpg 300w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/pg.-7-ASO-Halloween-November-final-600x450.jpg 600w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/pg.-7-ASO-Halloween-November-final-768x576.jpg 768w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/pg.-7-ASO-Halloween-November-final.jpg 1000w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-111692" class="wp-caption-text">ASO Halloween Party</figcaption></figure>
<p>On Friday, October 25, students gathered for the ASO Halloween Party, and students were encouraged to bring pumpkins for a painting/carving contest, as well as participating in a costume contest for prizes! There was a turnout of over 20 people, and students enjoyed each other’s company while playing games inside, with amazing food barbecued by students and Prof. Barlow Der Mugrdechian. There was a large amount of dessert as well.</p>
<p>On Friday, November 22, ASO hosted a Friendsgiving Potluck. This event had an amazing turnout, with over 35 students present. There were many team-based activities and games, including cup pong, a maze relay, blindfolded challenges, partnered relays, and more!</p>
<p>The evening was filled with laughter and fun, and the students enjoyed trying the foods brought by their friends.</p>
<figure id="attachment_111693" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-111693" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img decoding="async" class="size-small wp-image-111693" src="https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/ASO-2024-OCT-logo-300x231.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="231" srcset="https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/ASO-2024-OCT-logo-300x231.jpg 300w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/ASO-2024-OCT-logo-600x463.jpg 600w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/ASO-2024-OCT-logo-1200x926.jpg 1200w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/ASO-2024-OCT-logo-768x593.jpg 768w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/ASO-2024-OCT-logo-1536x1185.jpg 1536w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/ASO-2024-OCT-logo.jpg 2001w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-111693" class="wp-caption-text">ASO Logo</figcaption></figure>
<p>The new ASO crewnecks for the school year were also debuted during this event and many got purchased!</p>
<p>The Executive Board plans on hosting a December event for its members and encourages new students to attend.</p>
<p>Keep your eye out for upcoming information about it! You can follow ASO activities on Instagram @fresnostateaso.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/armenian-students-organization-has-active-fall-2024-semester/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>“Portrayal of Women in Armenian Literature” by Dr. David Zakarian</title>
		<link>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/portrayal-of-women-in-armenian-literature-by-dr-david-zakarian/</link>
					<comments>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/portrayal-of-women-in-armenian-literature-by-dr-david-zakarian/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[By Anahid Valencia, Staff Writer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 20:02:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ethnic Supplements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hye Sharzhoom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://fscollegian.com/?p=111687</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Anahid Valencia Staff Writer “My work attempts to build this narrative that we have another story, we have a real story, we have the original story that we could and should bring to the surface,” said Dr. David Zakarian in his lecture titled “The Portrayal of Women in Early Armenian Literature,” given on Thursday, October...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Anahid Valencia</strong></p>
<p><em>Staff Writer</em></p>
<p>“My work attempts to build this narrative that we have another story, we have a real story, we have the original story that we could and should bring to the surface,” said Dr. David Zakarian in his lecture titled “The Portrayal of Women in Early Armenian Literature,” given on Thursday, October 17, 2024. Dr. Zakarian’s lecture was part of the Armenian Studies Program Fall Lecture series and was supported by the Leon S. Peters Foundation.</p>
<p>In his presentation, Dr. Zakarian discussed the role of women in the Christianization of Armenia, the canons, or “rules” of ancient Armenia, and the position of women in the church today. At the end of the lecture, Dr. Zakarian opened the discussion to the audience, who were encouraged to ask questions and make comments.</p>
<p>Dr. Zakarian, the newly appointed Haig and Isabel Berberian Professor of Armenian Studies, began by posing a question – “what was the role of Armenian women during a time in which men wrote all of the literature?” Furthermore, he questioned the concept of the patriarchy being considered a tradition in Armenian culture.</p>
<p>Dr. Zakarian discussed the Christianization of Armenia in the fourth century CE, highlighting two women in particular, Sandukht, daughter of King Sanatruk, and Hripsime, a nun. Before Armenia became Christian, Zoroastrianism was the main religion, and it was during this time that St. Thaddeus, one of Christ’s apostles, was preaching Christianity at King Sanatruk’s court.</p>
<p>Sandukht became a devoted follower of St. Thaddeus and began preaching about Christ and converting people, which ultimately led her father to kill her. According to tradition, following Sandukht’s martyrdom, 2,000 people converted to Christianity, earning her what should have been a respected place in history. However, Dr. Zakarian explained that Sandukht is not given nearly enough credit for her role in the Christianization of Armenia and, for some in the audience, this was their first time hearing about her sacrifice.</p>
<p>“If we want to write the history of any people, we can’t just ignore at least 50% of the population, which were women,” said Dr. Zakarian.</p>
<p>Furthermore, Hripsime fleeing to Armenia to escape Emperor Diocletian’s marriage proposal ended up changing the course of Armenian history. When King Trdat the Great, who had 13 years earlier thrown Gregory into a pit for his refusal to worship the pagan goddess Anahid, fell in love with Hripsime, he decided to try and take her by force. Hripsime, however, defeated King Trdat and was then martyred along with her other companions. King Trdat, because of his sinful behavior, was turned into a wild boar. Thanks to the king’s sister, Khosrovidukht, Gregory was discovered to be alive, brought out of the pit, and healed King Trdat. Because of Gregory’s vision and Hripsime’s sacrifice, Armenia ultimately adopted Christianity.</p>
<p>“The first Armenian churches were built in the places where these virgins, St. Hripsime and her companions, were killed,” explained Dr. Zakarian. “They laid the foundation of the Armenian Church both physically by being buried under these churches, and symbolically, as it was their sacrifice that brought about Armenia’s Christianization.”</p>
<p>Dr. Zakarian then addressed whether the patriarchy is actually embedded within Armenian tradition by discussing the canons of ancient Armenia. His findings show that despite the patriarchal nature of the Armenian society, the ecclesiastical authorities imposed the same punishments on both men and women, suggesting a sense of equality that Armenians had since early times, most likely caused by the pre-Christian worldview of Armenians.</p>
<p>Dr. Zakarian shared a message by Catholicos Aram I of the Great House of Cilicia, who argued that the equality of men and women is a fundamental part of Christianity. Dr. Zakarian also spoke about deaconesses in the Armenian Apostolic Church – a concept that is foreign to many. A female deacon was ordained in an Armenian diasporic community in Iran, and Dr. Zakarian explained the significance of this occurring outside of Armenia. He further emphasized that throughout Armenian history, the portrayal of women – whether as empowered figures with full rights and responsibilities or as secondary figures largely excluded from such roles – has appeared to rest on the personal choices of individual church leaders.</p>
<p>The Armenian Apostolic Church has yet to implement this concept of female deacons to its full extent, however, Zakarian expressed his gratitude that it seems to have begun to.</p>
<p>Indeed, because of his research, Dr. Zakarian has been able to unveil a history which was hidden from a large part of the Armenian community – proving that the pen truly is mightier than the sword.</p>
<p>“This is something that no one speaks about, and I realized that I needed to do that,” concluded Dr. Zakarian.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/portrayal-of-women-in-armenian-literature-by-dr-david-zakarian/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hawk Khatcherian Presents Talk on Campus on “Khatchkars: Emblematic Art of the Armenians”</title>
		<link>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/hawk-khatcherian-presents-talk-on-campus-on-khatchkars-emblematic-art-of-the-armenians/</link>
					<comments>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/hawk-khatcherian-presents-talk-on-campus-on-khatchkars-emblematic-art-of-the-armenians/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[By Lori Agazarian, Staff Writer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 20:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hye Sharzhoom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://fscollegian.com/?p=111684</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Lori Agazarian Staff Writer &#160; The Fresno State Armenian Studies Program and the Armenian General Benevolent Union, Greater Fresno Chapter, hosted noted photographer Hrair Hawk Khatcherian on Thursday, November 14, to discuss his research on khatchkars and their connection to Armenian culture, art, and history. The lecture, “Khatchkars: Emblematic Art of Armenians,” was part of...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Lori Agazarian</strong></p>
<p><em>Staff Writer</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The Fresno State Armenian Studies Program and the Armenian General Benevolent Union, Greater Fresno Chapter, hosted noted photographer Hrair Hawk Khatcherian on Thursday, November 14, to discuss his research on <em>khatchkars</em> and their connection to Armenian culture, art, and history. The lecture, “Khatchkars: Emblematic Art of Armenians,” was part of the Grace and Paul Shahinian Armenian Christian Arts Series at Fresno State, established thanks to the support of Mr. Dean V. Shahinian.</p>
<p>The Armenian Studies Pro-gram held a reception prior to the lecture, with food and conversation, and featuring live music from the Andrew Hagopian Trio (Andrew Hagopian, Jonathan Chardukian, and Michael Mazman).</p>
<p>Khatcherian is an international photographer, who was born in Lebanon, but now lives in Canada. He has traveled to Armenia over 150 times throughout his thirty adventurous years of documenting Armenian culture, photographing monasteries, <em>khatchkars</em>, manuscripts, churches, and so much more. From balancing on rooftops, to hiking miles off the beaten track, Khatcherian has captured the beauty and history of Armenian <em>khatchkars</em> and compared their art and symbolism to Armenian manuscripts and churches.</p>
<p>Khatcherian recently published a book titled <em>Khatchkar: Art &amp; Soul – A Visual Journey</em>, where he shares his photos and compares them to notable manuscripts and miniature paintings. He started his presentation the same way that he began his book, with a quote – “In the beginning, God created the heavens and the earth.” He included an image of a manuscript that depicts the first seven days of God’s creation and followed this with a manuscript depicting the original sin of Adam and Eve. He then compared this to a <em>khatchkar</em> that depicted an image of Eve presenting the fruit to Adam carved on the bottom. There is much biblical influence found throughout all Armenian art, especially <em>khatchkars</em>.</p>
<p>Other examples Khatcherian researched through his photography are the Annunciation manuscript and <em>khatchkar</em> parallel found in the Monastery of Geghard, the Nativity Scene in Etchmiadzin, and multiple crucifixion depictions. A notable crucifixion comparison between manuscripts and <em>khatchkars</em> is “The Sun and Moon,” which features the same symbolism in both works of art. Furthermore, Khatcherian showed a <em>khatchkar</em> where the crucifixion scene is represented with Jesus on the cross, which is very rare, in comparison to other art forms that depict only a cross.</p>
<p>All of Khatcherian’s research and findings have historical meaning and value, and through-out his visits to Armenia, he has seen the changes that recent history has brought to Armenia and its art. Armenia and Artsakh are filled with <em>khatchkars</em> that date back to 866AD and even earlier, as seen in the pagan “dragon stones” that have been converted to <em>khatchkars</em>. With the wars and trauma that Armenia has endured in the last few years, much of Armenia’s art and culture is being destroyed and lost.</p>
<p>Khatcherian visited the village of Lichk in Armenia in 2021 and photographed the many <em>khatchkars</em>. However, when he returned to that same spot in 2023, most of the <em>khatchkars</em> he had photographed had been bulldozed; this is only one example of the loss of Armenia art and culture in recent history.</p>
<p>Khatcherian is researching and documenting the unique and culturally rich beauty of Armenian art and <em>khatchkars</em>. His work is important in preserving the tangible elements of Armenia’s heritage.</p>
<p>Khatcherian’s book <em>Khatchkars</em> is available at: <u>https://naasr.org/products/khatchkar-art-and-soul-a-visual-journey</u>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/hawk-khatcherian-presents-talk-on-campus-on-khatchkars-emblematic-art-of-the-armenians/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Maddy Institute invites Robert Costa to hold political discussion at Fresno State</title>
		<link>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/the-maddy-institute-invites-robert-costa-to-hold-political-discussion-at-fresno-state/</link>
					<comments>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/the-maddy-institute-invites-robert-costa-to-hold-political-discussion-at-fresno-state/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[By Isaac Marquez, Reporter]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 05:11:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Editors' picks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[political discussion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robert Costa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the maddy institute]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://fscollegian.com/?p=111680</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Robert Costa, the CBS News chief election correspondent, continued his visit at Fresno State by speaking at the Satellite Student Union on Dec. 2 following a private luncheon and press briefing. Costa went on stage to talk with Blake Zante, the executive director of The Maddy Institute, at the Satellite Student Union at 5:30 p.m....]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Robert Costa, the CBS News chief election correspondent, continued his visit at Fresno State by speaking at the Satellite Student Union on Dec. 2 following <a href="https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/robert-costa-speaks-at-fresno-state-as-part-of-the-maddy-institute-speaker-series/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a private luncheon and press briefing</a>.</p>
<p>Costa went on stage to talk with Blake Zante, the executive director of <a href="https://maddyinstitute.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Maddy Institute</a>, at the Satellite Student Union at 5:30 p.m. They discussed the current political state of the United States as well as what the future may hold.</p>
<p>One main talking point was the importance of the Central Valley and California on the national scale.</p>
<p>“California, but especially the valley, is really now at a crossroads of American politics,” Costa said. “You’re seeing all the issues that have been dominant here for years are now rising up to the national conversation.”</p>
<p>He discussed issues of tariffs affecting farming and trade along with issues around water and how places like Pennsylvania, Michigan and other states are looking at the Central Valley to see how the situations have been handled.</p>
<p>The conversation also included how President-elect Donald Trump has transformed the Republican Party to center around him and his ideologies. He also brought up how he used modern media formats like podcasts to further extend his reach.</p>
<p>Costa then spoke about the Democratic Party and what the future may hold for it. Whether it’s Governor Gavin Newsome running for president in 2028 or Vice President Kamala Harris again, he highlighted the fact that California has the potential to be a major player in the coming years but to not count out the Republican population in the state.</p>
<p>“That&#8217;s not to say California is going to lurch right, but this expectation that California is a blue state, a deep blue state forever is not necessarily a guarantee,” Costa said.</p>
<p>Costa talked about his appreciation for organizations like The Maddy Institute and Fresno State students who strive to be engaged in the news and read the latest stories. He also added the importance of local journalism, especially non-profit organizations.</p>
<p>Following the discussion, Costa opened up for questions and then a quick meet and greet.</p>
<p>Christopher Washington, a Law Pathway student at Fresno City College, was a huge fan of Costa and appreciated his bipartisan discussion.</p>
<p>“Bipartisanship is extremely important in bridging the gap within our democracy and allowing people to have a seat at the table,” Washington said.</p>
<p>The event finished around 7:30 p.m. and Costa left Fresno State with gifts from the school. This included student-made honey, wine and olive oil which was given to him by President Saúl Jiménez-Sandoval.</p>
<p>Costa thanked The Maddy Institute for their goal of making the next generation focused on civic participation and organization.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/the-maddy-institute-invites-robert-costa-to-hold-political-discussion-at-fresno-state/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Losing skid continues for Fresno State men&#8217;s basketball at Santa Clara</title>
		<link>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/losing-skid-continues-for-fresno-state-mens-basketball-at-santa-clara/</link>
					<comments>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/losing-skid-continues-for-fresno-state-mens-basketball-at-santa-clara/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[By Vincent Ordonio, Reporter]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 06:54:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Men's Basketball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alex Crawford]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mykell Robinson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Santa Clara University]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zaon Collins]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://fscollegian.com/?p=111677</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Fresno State men’s basketball team (3-6) extended its losing streak to four as it lost 81-66 to Santa Clara University on Saturday, Dec. 7, at the Leavey Center. The Bulldogs were led by sophomore guard Zaon Collins as he recorded 17 points on an efficient 5-for-10 shooting from the field and 2-for-4 from beyond...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Fresno State men’s basketball team (3-6) extended its losing streak to four as it lost 81-66 to Santa Clara University on Saturday, Dec. 7, at the Leavey Center.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Bulldogs were led by sophomore guard Zaon Collins as he recorded 17 points on an efficient 5-for-10 shooting from the field and 2-for-4 from beyond the arc to go along with his five rebounds, six assists and four steals.</span></p>
<div class='infographicwidget'><div class='center'></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="qme"> <a href="https://t.co/BdCL8WzFh7">pic.twitter.com/BdCL8WzFh7</a></p>
<p>— Fresno State Men’s Basketball (@FresnoStateMBB) <a href="https://twitter.com/FresnoStateMBB/status/1865554289525170273?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 8, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div></div><div class='clear'></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Junior forward Mykell Robinson also contributed with 15 points and seven rebounds.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Although the Bulldogs had surges of production on both ends of the court late in the second half, it wasn’t enough as the Broncos’ hot 3-point shooting kept the ‘Dogs at bay. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">39 of the Broncos’ 81 points came from beyond the arc, going 13-for-31 (41.9%) all game and 6-for-13 (46.2%) from 3-point range in the second half.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This was also senior guard Jalen Weaver’s first game back since </span><a href="https://fscollegian.com/2024/11/mor-seck-leads-dogs-to-dominating-victory-against-panthers/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nov. 20 against Prairie View A&amp;M</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, putting junior guard Amar Aguillard back on the bench. In his game back, Weaver recorded two points, three rebounds and two steals.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another change to the starting lineup was junior forward Alex Crawford, who started in place of junior Mor Seck. Head Coach Vance Walberg opted for a small-ball lineup with freshman forward Elijah Price at the center position. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In his starting role, Crawford had a solid game pitching in with 13 points on an efficient 5-for-7 (71.43%) shooting to go with his season-high three steals.</span></p>
<p><b>What happened</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To open the first half Crawford scored the Bulldogs’ first 4 points, but the Broncos answered with by going 1-for-2 from the free throw line and a 3-pointer to make things an even 4-4 to start the game.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Minutes later, Augillard and Seck were the first Bulldogs off the bench to replace Price and Weaver. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As the first half went on, the Bulldogs looked to drive to the paint, but it didn’t come easy as the Broncos’ defense was anchored by 7-footer junior center Christoph Tilly. Nonetheless, the ‘Dogs remained persistent to score inside.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the late minutes of the first half, both teams were trading 3-pointers as Robinson led the charge with his shooting to keep the ‘Dogs in the game. Despite that, the Broncos had the slight edge to close the first half as they led 36-25.</span></p>
<div class='infographicwidget'><div class='center'></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">TRIPLE  <a href="https://t.co/B89XAmKe7f">pic.twitter.com/B89XAmKe7f</a></p>
<p>— Fresno State Men’s Basketball (@FresnoStateMBB) <a href="https://twitter.com/FresnoStateMBB/status/1865558252001665139?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 8, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div></div><div class='clear'></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Heading into halftime, the Bulldogs were out rebounded 18-26, allowing nine offensive rebounds. The Bulldogs, who average 14 fast-break points per game, were held to zero fastbreak points in the first half–uncharacteristic for a team that ranks second in the nation in tempo.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Much like the first half, Crawford led the Bulldogs early in the second half as he scored the ‘Dogs’ first six points which sparked a surge on offense as Price pitched in with four quick points to make it a 9-point game.</span></p>
<div class='infographicwidget'><div class='center'></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Okay AC  <a href="https://t.co/EoN2O62m0K">pic.twitter.com/EoN2O62m0K</a></p>
<p>— Fresno State Men’s Basketball (@FresnoStateMBB) <a href="https://twitter.com/FresnoStateMBB/status/1865564954990194834?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 8, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div></div><div class='clear'></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But the Broncos responded as they increased their lead to 17 points, making the score 59-42 as they continued to sink their 3-pointers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a late-game effort, the Bulldogs pressed up full-court, which worked as they forced turnovers and turned them into points. Even so, it was too late, as the Broncos drained the dagger 3-pointer in the corner en route to their 81-66 win.</span></p>
<p><b>What’s next</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Bulldogs continue their road trip as they get another chance to snap their four-game losing streak against Brigham Young University on Wednesday, Dec. 11, at 6 p.m.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/losing-skid-continues-for-fresno-state-mens-basketball-at-santa-clara/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Photo Essay: Fresno State men&#8217;s basketball vs San Diego State</title>
		<link>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/photo-essay-fresno-state-mens-basketball-vs-san-diego-state/</link>
					<comments>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/photo-essay-fresno-state-mens-basketball-vs-san-diego-state/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[By Ryan Caruso, Chase Gauthier]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 23:30:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Men's Basketball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Multimedia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photo Galleries (7265)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amar Augillard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elijah Price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jasir Tremble]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mykell Robinson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vance walberg]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://fscollegian.com/?p=111657</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="photowrap">
	<div class='sfiphotowrap sfiphotowrap modal-photo' data-photo-ids='111658,111666,111659,111669,111660,111665,111661,111667,111662,111664,111663,111668,111670' data-story-id='111657'>
		<div id='storypageslideshow' style='max-width: 400px; margin: 0 auto;'>
			<div class="slideshowwrap" data-ratio="0.66666666666667">
				<img decoding="async" src="https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Amar-Augillard-800x1200.jpg" class="slideshow-photo" alt="Amar Augillard" data-width="800" data-height="1200" />
				<a class='modal-photo' href='#slideshow' aria-haspopup='dialog' aria-expanded='false' aria-label='View larger version of image.'>
					<div class='slideshow-enlarge'>
						<div class="fa fa-clone slideshow-icon"></div>
						<div class='slideshow-title'>Gallery<span class='v-divider'> &bull; </span>13 Photos</div>
					</div>
				</a>
			</div>
							<div class="captionboxmittop">
					<div class="photocredit"><a href="https://fscollegian.com/staff_name/ryan-caruso-the-collegian/">Ryan Caruso/The Collegian</a></div>											<div class="photocaption">
							Guard Amar Augillard (1) looks on. 						</div>
									</div>
			
		</div>
	</div>
</div>
<div class="photobottom"></div>
<div class="clear"></div>
<div class="newssourcephotos" data-photoids="111658,111666,111659,111669,111660,111665,111661,111667,111662,111664,111663,111668,111670"></div>

]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/photo-essay-fresno-state-mens-basketball-vs-san-diego-state/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Opinion: Voter spite is jeopardizing our future</title>
		<link>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/opinion-voter-spite-is-jeopardizing-our-future/</link>
					<comments>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/opinion-voter-spite-is-jeopardizing-our-future/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[By Ashley Cortez, Reporter]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 22:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Editors' picks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2024 presidential election]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://fscollegian.com/?p=111654</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[America’s empathy problem goes beyond indifference; it’s rooted in a self-focused, almost spiteful way of thinking that’s holding our future hostage. How many people do you know who voted? How many do you know who didn’t? Many Americans cast their votes not to support constructive policies but to fuel their own anger, latching onto candidates...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>America’s empathy problem goes beyond indifference; it’s rooted in a self-focused, almost spiteful way of thinking that’s holding our future hostage.</p>
<p>How many people do you know who voted? How many do you know who didn’t?</p>
<p>Many Americans cast their votes not to support constructive policies but to fuel their own anger, latching onto candidates that validate their personal resentments. Others do not vote at all because ‘their vote won’t change anything’.</p>
<p><strong>Why did minorities vote for Trump?<br />
</strong><br />
About a quarter of Hispanic respondents <a href="https://www.edisonresearch.com/latino-male-voters-shift-toward-trump-in-2024-election/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">in an Edison Research exit poll</a> said most immigrants in the country without documentation should be deported to the countries they came from, compared with 40% of voters overall in the poll.</p>
<p>Others in the Latino community seem to like Trump for his economic policies and the myth of cheaper groceries.</p>
<p>&#8220;Out here, you pay $5 for a dozen eggs. It used to be $1, or even 99 cents,&#8221; said Samuel Negron in Pennsylvania <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cze3yr77j9wo" target="_blank" rel="noopener">for BBC</a>, &#8220;A lot of us have woken up, in my opinion, from Democratic lies that things have been better. We realized things were better then.&#8221;</p>
<p>Focusing on smaller aspects like the price of groceries or gas, it seems like voters will choose whoever will benefit them personally, no matter the cost or consequence for others.</p>
<p>In recent years, voting has become less about policy and more about <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/opinion/columnist/2024/10/31/voting-trump-harris-economy-inflation/75836771007/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">personal vendettas</a>.</p>
<p>People aren’t voting based on data or policy proposals. Because, if they were, they’d know that economists say that Trump’s economic policies will <a href="https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/true-dangers-trump-presidency-economic-plans" target="_blank" rel="noopener">likely result in</a> prices going up rather than down.</p>
<p>Already, businesses are preparing for the high costs they’ll face with the tariffs Trump has campaigned on.</p>
<p>“&#8230;Tariffs are paid by the companies or entities importing goods and not by the countries themselves. This means the cost of buying products from overseas would rise sharply,” said Neil Saunders, Managing Director and Retail Analyst at GlobalData Retail, <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/11/06/trump-proposed-tariffs-consumer-prices.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">in a research note</a> on Nov. 6.</p>
<p>Despite many economists sharing these views, U.S. voters have proven they’d rather vote with their emotions and the belief that “they” (Democrats) are the enemy.</p>
<p>Any fact or information that doesn’t align with what Trump has claimed is flat-out ignored. Their votes are about what affirms their anger in the moment, reinforcing a cycle of hate and resentment.</p>
<p><strong>So why exactly does this matter?<br />
</strong><br />
We often hear that people vote based on “kitchen-table issues,” but voting out of fear or anger only satisfies the immediate need for validation, which is already being speculated to come back and bite the entire country.</p>
<p>Family and community should be strong motivators for voting, but instead, they’ve been swapped out for what&#8217;s “best” for ourselves, feeding a destructive cycle of short-sighted choices over real, sustainable solutions.</p>
<p>Blood is thick, yes, but according to America, it’s nothing compared to the lie of cheap groceries and lower gas prices.</p>
<p>This immediate self-gratification ignores the needs of our future generations, and the false promise of your own gain will harm children more than it claims to help.</p>
<p>Like the gradual heating of a bathtub, the erosion of rights often goes unnoticed until it’s too late.</p>
<p>Trump’s presidency ended years ago, yet the consequences are still playing out, and with his reelection, we may see the rise of even more fundamental human rights being stripped away. Many of <a href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/world-news/2024/11/07/will-project-2025-help-trump-or-prove-assault-on-democracy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Trump’s previous administration</a> had a hand in <a href="https://www.aclu.org/project-2025-explained" target="_blank" rel="noopener">writing Project 2025</a>, which is designed to gut abortion access, roll back trans rights, and essentially turn America into a surveillance state by limiting our access to media that is considered a ‘vice’.</p>
<p>But these losses won’t just happen overnight; it’ll be the result of years of reactive voting without thinking about the long-term consequences.</p>
<p>The reality is that many of the challenges we now face are the result of decisions made long before we felt their effects.</p>
<p>Two years after Trump left office, the Republican majority in the Supreme Court was able to successfully overturn Roe v. Wade—an outcome that was decades in the making.</p>
<p>The impact of Roe V. Wade’s loss has been seen most notably in <a href="https://people.com/texas-teen-suffering-miscarriage-dies-due-to-abortion-ban-8738512" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nevaeh Crain’s story</a>, which despite happening a year ago, has recently made headlines throughout the U.S.</p>
<p>At six months pregnant, Crain began experiencing symptoms like a headache, fever, nausea, and vomiting, which were later found to be caused by sepsis from a miscarriage.</p>
<p>Living in Texas, she and her family had to wait to receive any reproductive medical care until she began bleeding heavily from her nose, mouth, and between her legs. Crain passed away in the intensive care unit just hours after her mother desperately begged doctors to intervene.</p>
<p>While Roe V. Wade and reproductive rights is a common Democratic talking point, it’s not the only threat to women following Trump’s reelection.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.aol.com/news/body-choice-women-report-rise-171545142.html?guccounter=1&amp;guce_referrer=aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbS8&amp;guce_referrer_sig=AQAAAIhnF_3LpV56S9Ox9kt8XSGBo-y-2jlppuxczOqlQrXfYah08_bEf31_zDcrFwtqvAyRlSIa2LU0AoA-fF76YWnZr3TGJRDXlqPjTIk2h9FOuVljaR6kxaaezilInSChhY-EbptgmRGzCxiJKPBYyZVWFj_yCfBHB_eibwWBIwaK" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AOL reports</a> that many women have faced men writing “your body, my choice” on their <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@camichurro_123/video/7434335152005729579" target="_blank" rel="noopener">social media posts</a>, as an inverse to the feminist slogan “my body, my choice”.</p>
<p>The phrase has <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@emazzaspams/video/7434203599216856351" target="_blank" rel="noopener">quickly gained traction</a> on TikTok, where women have expressed feeling that their bodies no longer belong to them in the wake of the presidential election results.</p>
<p>We have effectively built a pathway for these types of men to feel comfortable saying these things without consequence, setting up the next generations to lose.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not only an issue with our presidential votes, but local ones too.</p>
<p>California has successfully voted against <a href="https://calmatters.org/california-voter-guide-2024/propositions/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">three more ‘liberal’ propositions</a> on their state ballot, restricting the state as a whole.</p>
<p>Proposition 6, which aimed to end involuntary labor by incarcerated individuals, was rejected with 54.8% voting ‘No’. Proposition 32, which proposed raising the minimum wage to $17/hr and $18/hr starting January 1, 2025, was also rejected with 51.8% voting ‘No’. Proposition 33, which would repeal the ban on local rent control, was rejected with 61.4% voting ‘No’.</p>
<p>Voting based only on present convenience, or on what’s right in front of us at the moment, sacrifices the needs and rights of those who come after us.</p>
<p>Take climate change, for example. During Trump’s first term, he withdrew the United States from the Paris Climate Agreement, citing the “unfair economic burden” it placed on American workers. The decision was <a href="https://www.npr.org/2020/11/03/930312701/u-s-officially-leaving-paris-climate-agreement" target="_blank" rel="noopener">highly protested</a> by various scientists and science advocacy groups.</p>
<p>In other administrations, such as Bill Clinton&#8217;s, acts that were designed to reduce the negative effects of climate change <a href="https://unfccc.int/kyoto_protocol" target="_blank" rel="noopener">had trouble getting backed</a> by the Senate.</p>
<p>The Republican Senate majority shows just how powerful short-sighted voting can be. The Senate has the power to confirm judicial nominees of the Supreme Court, making it all too easy for Trump to <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/dispatches/donald-trumps-supreme-court-majority-could-easily-rule-through-2045" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reshape the courts for decades</a>.</p>
<p>With Senate support, he could urge for current justices to retire, and replace them with much younger candidates that share his views, locking us all in for <a href="https://www.google.com/amp/s/amp.cnn.com/cnn/2024/11/08/politics/trump-grasps-unprecedented-power-supreme-court-immunity" target="_blank" rel="noopener">that lifetime appointment</a>.</p>
<p>“I expect Alito to announce his retirement in the spring of 2025…I hear some folks say that Thomas won’t retire,” wrote Ed Whelan, a conservative lawyer, in <a href="https://www.nationalreview.com/bench-memos/perpetuating-a-strong-conservative-majority-on-the-supreme-court/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an essay</a> on the National Review&#8217;s Bench Memos blog, “But it would be foolish of him to risk repeating Ruth Bader Ginsburg’s mistake… So expect him to decide to retire in the spring of 2026.”</p>
<p>Rights we may take for granted, like what happened with <a href="https://www.npr.org/2022/06/24/1102305878/supreme-court-abortion-roe-v-wade-decision-overturn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reproductive choice</a>, could continue being steadily rolled back as the Supreme Court sees fit.</p>
<p>Future generations of Americans will live in a country shaped by today’s selfish votes, where affordable housing and essential freedoms are out of reach.</p>
<p>To move forward, we must vote with empathy, valuing long-term stability over short-term satisfaction.</p>
<p>It’s time to prioritize the common good over fleeting anger because by focusing on winning in the moment, we’re setting the nation up to lose the future.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/opinion-voter-spite-is-jeopardizing-our-future/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fresno State&#8217;s production of &#8220;Red Velvet&#8221; shares untold Black history</title>
		<link>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/red-velvet-preview/</link>
					<comments>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/red-velvet-preview/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[By Oscar Alexander, Reporter]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 21:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Theatre]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fresno State Theatre]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Red Velvet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stage play]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/red-velvet-preview/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Lolita Chakrabarti’s “Red Velvet” is set to make its Fresno theatre premiere tonight as Fresno State’s University Theatre’s third show of the 2024-25 mainstage season. Directed by Fresno State theater professor Brad Myers, the production is set against the backdrop of 19th century London. The play follows the true story of Ira Aldridge, the first...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lolita Chakrabarti’s “Red Velvet” is set to make its Fresno theatre premiere tonight as Fresno State’s University Theatre’s third show of the 2024-25 mainstage season.</p>
<p>Directed by Fresno State theater professor Brad Myers, the production is set against the backdrop of 19th century London. The play follows the true story of Ira Aldridge, the first Black man to play Shakespeare’s highly-revered Othello on a major English stage.</p>
<p>The story sees Aldridge in his later years, with flashbacks that showcase the racism, oppression and triumphs he faced throughout his life and career.</p>
<p>“This was right after slavery was abolished [in London],” lead actor Jimmy Haynie told The Collegian. “It was extremely controversial and scandalous to have a Black man perform on stage during this time and previously, it had only been done in blackface by Edmund Kean.”</p>
<figure id="attachment_111652" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-111652" style="width: 742px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class=" wp-image-111652" src="https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Red-Velvet-3-min-600x400.jpg" alt="" width="742" height="495" srcset="https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Red-Velvet-3-min-600x400.jpg 600w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Red-Velvet-3-min-1200x800.jpg 1200w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Red-Velvet-3-min-768x512.jpg 768w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Red-Velvet-3-min-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Red-Velvet-3-min-300x200.jpg 300w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Red-Velvet-3-min.jpg 2001w" sizes="(max-width: 742px) 100vw, 742px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-111652" class="wp-caption-text">Jimmy Haynie (pictured far right) and fellow cast members during rehearsal for &#8220;Red Velvet.&#8221; (Courtesy of Miguel Gastelum)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Haynie said he was excited to portray such an important historical figure but was skeptical about the play’s authenticity before auditioning.</p>
<p>“I was unsure how to feel about a black story being told from a non black perspective,” Haynie said. “But early on in the process, I think what made me most excited was being able to tell this important story. I think people like him deserve to be heard about and learned about, because he, and we know this from so many wonderful black people in history, a lot of our history is forgotten.”</p>
<p>The show marks Myers’ final directorial feat after a 42-year-long career.</p>
<p>“When I first was looking for a show for my swan song I read an awful lot of plays, more plays than usual, because I was looking for something very particular,” Myers told The Collegian. “I wanted a piece of theater that I would be really passionate about, and I wanted a show that was really good for our theater arts majors…I finally came across Red Velvet, and that was a very exciting find.”</p>
<p>Myers has previously directed Fresno State productions of “Much Ado About Nothing,” “The Private Life of the Master Race” and <a href="https://cah.fresnostate.edu/theatrearts/faculty-staff/faculty/myers.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">many more.</a></p>
<p>With “Red Velvet,” he hopes to deliver a fresh take on a relatively unknown story.</p>
<p>“I think that this play can be more impactful, has the potential to be more impactful,” Myers said. “It doesn&#8217;t just feel like just an old history lesson. The issues are certainly of racism and misogyny. Ira Aldridge was also an American. He was an American-born actor, and so there&#8217;s xenophobia in the play, because they&#8217;re mortified. There&#8217;s some voices in the play that really think that they need to preserve the traditions, the English traditions of Shakespeare, and that that does not include having a black man play a fellow, or an American stepping onto the stage in a Shakespearean play.”</p>
<figure id="attachment_111650" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-111650" style="width: 868px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-111650" src="https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Red-Velvet-2-min-600x400.jpg" alt="" width="868" height="579" srcset="https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Red-Velvet-2-min-600x400.jpg 600w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Red-Velvet-2-min-1200x800.jpg 1200w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Red-Velvet-2-min-768x512.jpg 768w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Red-Velvet-2-min-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Red-Velvet-2-min-300x200.jpg 300w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Red-Velvet-2-min.jpg 2001w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 868px) 100vw, 868px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-111650" class="wp-caption-text">Jimmy Haynie (pictured left) and fellow cast members during rehearsal for &#8220;Red Velvet.&#8221; (Courtesy of Miguel Gastelum)</figcaption></figure>
<p>“I&#8217;m satisfied,” Myers said. “I don&#8217;t know that I&#8217;ve really had an end in vision, if that makes sense. I haven&#8217;t had an end in sight. It&#8217;s just do the best I can with every show I take on. You know, do the best I can given where I am at in my own artistic development, and I feel that that’s happened.”</p>
<p>Myers says the goal for this production is to inspire people to not give up on their dreams, even when it seems like the odds are stacked against them.</p>
<p>“I think his story is inspirational,” Myers said. “And for a lot of people today who encounter obstacles because of who they are, for whatever reason, the color of their skin, their gender, their sexual identity, anything like that. Ira Aldrich fought through that adversity, and ultimately his whole life was a real triumph over that adversity.”</p>
<p>Haynie also agrees that Aldridge’s story is one that will inspire.</p>
<p>“I think people who will take the most away from it are those who are driven and…are working towards those goals,” Haynie said. “It’s very telling of the time nowadays…we still struggle with inclusion and diversity in in our profession.”</p>
<p>Performances will run Dec. 6-7, 10-14, and will start at 7:30 p.m. at the John W. Wright Theatre on the Fresno State campus. An additional performance will be held Dec. 8 at 2 p.m.</p>
<p>Doors open 30 minutes before curtain and latecomers will not be allowed in, according to the press release.</p>
<p>Tickets are $20 for adults, $18 for Fresno State faculty, staff, alumni and military and $10 for all students.</p>
<p>The box office is open 12-3 p.m. on Tuesday-Thursday, and one hour before each performance.</p>
<p>Parking is free for shows on Friday through Sunday night. For shows on Tuesday through Thursday night, parking permits are required and can be purchased at dispensers in parking lots on campus for $5.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/red-velvet-preview/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fresno State women&#8217;s basketball runs away with victory over UC Merced</title>
		<link>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/fresno-state-womens-basketball-runs-away-with-victory-over-uc-merced/</link>
					<comments>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/fresno-state-womens-basketball-runs-away-with-victory-over-uc-merced/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[By Vincent Ordonio, Reporter]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 06:35:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Women's Basketball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jaime white]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mia Jacobs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://fscollegian.com/?p=111640</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Despite being down two starters, the Fresno State women’s basketball team (7-3) came away with a win against the University of California, Merced 83-60 on Thursday, Dec. 5, at the Save Mart Center. Senior guard Saga Ukkonen joined sophomore guard Taija Sta. Maria (lower leg injury) on the injury list. Head Coach Jaime White said...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite being down two starters, the Fresno State women’s basketball team (7-3) came away with a win against the University of California, Merced 83-60 on Thursday, Dec. 5, at the Save Mart Center.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Senior guard Saga Ukkonen joined sophomore guard Taija Sta. Maria (lower leg injury) on the injury list. Head Coach Jaime White said she’s managing an injury from the game </span><a href="https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/jacobs-shines-as-fresno-state-womens-basketball-bounces-back-with-ot-win-over-ut-martin/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">against the University of Tennessee at Martin</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> last week and her return is imminent. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We need her rested and she’s day-to-day right now,” White said. “I think she’s doing really well, so we’re hoping to have her back soon.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Freshman guard Danae Powell took over point guard duties and impressed her coach on both ends of the court in Ukkonen’s place.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I think [Danae] runs the offense really well, sees the open person; you saw those baseline passes, I thought she did a good job there,” White said. “She’s also tough defensively and is able to defend in a lot of different ways, so we’re really excited to see her get some opportunities.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Powell recorded a season-high five assists along with seven points in her first start of the season. Junior forward Mia Jacobs also pitched in as she recorded her seventh double-double of the season with 18 points and 11 rebounds to go along with her three steals. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jacobs logged a new season-high of four 3-pointers against the Bobcats which she thought was important as it allows for herself and others to score in the paint.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Keep [shooting] and knowing the next one’s going to go in is really important,” Jacobs said. “Then drawing the defense out after you hit a couple [3-pointers], then that’s when you start to drive or get pull ups and find teammates.”</span></p>
<p><b>What happened </b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jacobs led the team in the first quarter as she scored the team’s first seven points, but the Bobcats kept themselves in the game after a slow start defensively for the Bulldogs. The ‘Dogs closed out the quarter with a 17-11 lead after a well-balanced offensive game plan- driving to the paint and kicking it out for 3-pointers. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To open the second quarter, the Bulldogs went on a 12-5 run fueled by their 3-point shooting as Powell and junior guard drained one 3-pointer each, which opened up opportunities in the paint.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But the Bobcats were still in the game heading into halftime as they were also making their 3-pointers, with the Bulldogs leading 38-27.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At the half, the Bulldogs played strong defense as they forced the Bobcats to eight turnovers while recording three blocks and five steals. They also held the Bobcats to 9-of-32 (28.1%) shooting from the field and did a good job at closing out on 3-point shooters as the Bobcats only attempted eight 3-pointers and made three of them. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the third quarter, the Bulldogs gave the Bobcats a different look on defense as they pressed up full court, which resulted in four turnovers and three steals for the ‘Dogs. The Bulldogs also carried their hot shooting into the third quarter as they went 4-of-8 from the 3-point line, contributing to their 63-44 lead as the quarter came to a close.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the final quarter, the Bulldogs kept the Bobcats at a distance as they maintained their lead throughout the quarter in route to winning the game 83-60.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After finding success with a zone defense early in the season, White felt it wasn’t as effective this game, which led to the team pressing up full court in the third quarter. The change helped the team in a rhythm to pull away with the win.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite the considerable deficit, the Bobcats had their way from beyond the arc, shooting 9-of-19 from three. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I don’t think our zone was as good tonight, but I liked our press; our press really got us back into it,” White said. “In the second half, we allowed too many threes, and credit to their team. I told their coach, &#8216;That&#8217;s the best somebody’s played against our zone,’ so we’re going to have to work on some things.”</span></p>
<p><b>What’s next</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Bulldogs get a brief break before heading to the Galen Center next Tuesday to take on the No. 6 Trojans of the University of Southern California (USC). </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It will be another tough test for Fresno State with USC possessing a pair of first team Associated Press preseason </span><a href="https://apnews.com/article/college-basketball-ap-allamerica-team-447452800081a79ebcf587c16e19f35c"><span style="font-weight: 400;">All-Americans</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in JuJu Watkins and Kiki Iriafen.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/fresno-state-womens-basketball-runs-away-with-victory-over-uc-merced/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
