<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Collegian</title>
	<atom:link href="https://fscollegian.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://fscollegian.com</link>
	<description>Fresno State&#039;s student-run newspaper</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 23:30:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Photo Essay: Fresno State men&#8217;s basketball vs San Diego State</title>
		<link>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/photo-essay-fresno-state-mens-basketball-vs-san-diego-state/</link>
					<comments>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/photo-essay-fresno-state-mens-basketball-vs-san-diego-state/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[By Ryan Caruso, Chase Gauthier]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 23:30:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Men's Basketball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Multimedia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photo Galleries (7265)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amar Augillard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elijah Price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jasir Tremble]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mykell Robinson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vance walberg]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://fscollegian.com/?p=111657</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="photowrap">
	<div class='sfiphotowrap sfiphotowrap modal-photo' data-photo-ids='111658,111666,111659,111669,111660,111665,111661,111667,111662,111664,111663,111668,111670' data-story-id='111657'>
		<div id='storypageslideshow' style='max-width: 400px; margin: 0 auto;'>
			<div class="slideshowwrap" data-ratio="0.66666666666667">
				<img decoding="async" src="https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Amar-Augillard-800x1200.jpg" class="slideshow-photo" alt="Amar Augillard" data-width="800" data-height="1200" />
				<a class='modal-photo' href='#slideshow' aria-haspopup='dialog' aria-expanded='false' aria-label='View larger version of image.'>
					<div class='slideshow-enlarge'>
						<div class="fa fa-clone slideshow-icon"></div>
						<div class='slideshow-title'>Gallery<span class='v-divider'> &bull; </span>13 Photos</div>
					</div>
				</a>
			</div>
							<div class="captionboxmittop">
					<div class="photocredit"><a href="https://fscollegian.com/staff_name/ryan-caruso-the-collegian/">Ryan Caruso/The Collegian</a></div>											<div class="photocaption">
							Guard Amar Augillard (1) looks on. 						</div>
									</div>
			
		</div>
	</div>
</div>
<div class="photobottom"></div>
<div class="clear"></div>
<div class="newssourcephotos" data-photoids="111658,111666,111659,111669,111660,111665,111661,111667,111662,111664,111663,111668,111670"></div>

]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/photo-essay-fresno-state-mens-basketball-vs-san-diego-state/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Opinion: Voter spite is jeopardizing our future</title>
		<link>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/opinion-voter-spite-is-jeopardizing-our-future/</link>
					<comments>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/opinion-voter-spite-is-jeopardizing-our-future/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[By Ashley Cortez, Reporter]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 22:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2024 presidential election]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://fscollegian.com/?p=111654</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[America’s empathy problem goes beyond indifference; it’s rooted in a self-focused, almost spiteful way of thinking that’s holding our future hostage. How many people do you know who voted? How many do you know who didn’t? Many Americans cast their votes not to support constructive policies but to fuel their own anger, latching onto candidates...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>America’s empathy problem goes beyond indifference; it’s rooted in a self-focused, almost spiteful way of thinking that’s holding our future hostage.</p>
<p>How many people do you know who voted? How many do you know who didn’t?</p>
<p>Many Americans cast their votes not to support constructive policies but to fuel their own anger, latching onto candidates that validate their personal resentments. Others do not vote at all because ‘their vote won’t change anything’.</p>
<p><strong>Why did minorities vote for Trump?<br />
</strong><br />
About a quarter of Hispanic respondents <a href="https://www.edisonresearch.com/latino-male-voters-shift-toward-trump-in-2024-election/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">in an Edison Research exit poll</a> said most immigrants in the country without documentation should be deported to the countries they came from, compared with 40% of voters overall in the poll.</p>
<p>Others in the Latino community seem to like Trump for his economic policies and the myth of cheaper groceries.</p>
<p>&#8220;Out here, you pay $5 for a dozen eggs. It used to be $1, or even 99 cents,&#8221; said Samuel Negron in Pennsylvania <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cze3yr77j9wo" target="_blank" rel="noopener">for BBC</a>, &#8220;A lot of us have woken up, in my opinion, from Democratic lies that things have been better. We realized things were better then.&#8221;</p>
<p>Focusing on smaller aspects like the price of groceries or gas, it seems like voters will choose whoever will benefit them personally, no matter the cost or consequence for others.</p>
<p>In recent years, voting has become less about policy and more about <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/opinion/columnist/2024/10/31/voting-trump-harris-economy-inflation/75836771007/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">personal vendettas</a>.</p>
<p>People aren’t voting based on data or policy proposals. Because, if they were, they’d know that economists say that Trump’s economic policies will <a href="https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/true-dangers-trump-presidency-economic-plans" target="_blank" rel="noopener">likely result in</a> prices going up rather than down.</p>
<p>Already, businesses are preparing for the high costs they’ll face with the tariffs Trump has campaigned on.</p>
<p>“&#8230;Tariffs are paid by the companies or entities importing goods and not by the countries themselves. This means the cost of buying products from overseas would rise sharply,” said Neil Saunders, Managing Director and Retail Analyst at GlobalData Retail, <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/11/06/trump-proposed-tariffs-consumer-prices.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">in a research note</a> on Nov. 6.</p>
<p>Despite many economists sharing these views, U.S. voters have proven they’d rather vote with their emotions and the belief that “they” (Democrats) are the enemy.</p>
<p>Any fact or information that doesn’t align with what Trump has claimed is flat-out ignored. Their votes are about what affirms their anger in the moment, reinforcing a cycle of hate and resentment.</p>
<p><strong>So why exactly does this matter?<br />
</strong><br />
We often hear that people vote based on “kitchen-table issues,” but voting out of fear or anger only satisfies the immediate need for validation, which is already being speculated to come back and bite the entire country.</p>
<p>Family and community should be strong motivators for voting, but instead, they’ve been swapped out for what&#8217;s “best” for ourselves, feeding a destructive cycle of short-sighted choices over real, sustainable solutions.</p>
<p>Blood is thick, yes, but according to America, it’s nothing compared to the lie of cheap groceries and lower gas prices.</p>
<p>This immediate self-gratification ignores the needs of our future generations, and the false promise of your own gain will harm children more than it claims to help.</p>
<p>Like the gradual heating of a bathtub, the erosion of rights often goes unnoticed until it’s too late.</p>
<p>Trump’s presidency ended years ago, yet the consequences are still playing out, and with his reelection, we may see the rise of even more fundamental human rights being stripped away. Many of <a href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/world-news/2024/11/07/will-project-2025-help-trump-or-prove-assault-on-democracy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Trump’s previous administration</a> had a hand in <a href="https://www.aclu.org/project-2025-explained" target="_blank" rel="noopener">writing Project 2025</a>, which is designed to gut abortion access, roll back trans rights, and essentially turn America into a surveillance state by limiting our access to media that is considered a ‘vice’.</p>
<p>But these losses won’t just happen overnight; it’ll be the result of years of reactive voting without thinking about the long-term consequences.</p>
<p>The reality is that many of the challenges we now face are the result of decisions made long before we felt their effects.</p>
<p>Two years after Trump left office, the Republican majority in the Supreme Court was able to successfully overturn Roe v. Wade—an outcome that was decades in the making.</p>
<p>The impact of Roe V. Wade’s loss has been seen most notably in <a href="https://people.com/texas-teen-suffering-miscarriage-dies-due-to-abortion-ban-8738512" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nevaeh Crain’s story</a>, which despite happening a year ago, has recently made headlines throughout the U.S.</p>
<p>At six months pregnant, Crain began experiencing symptoms like a headache, fever, nausea, and vomiting, which were later found to be caused by sepsis from a miscarriage.</p>
<p>Living in Texas, she and her family had to wait to receive any reproductive medical care until she began bleeding heavily from her nose, mouth, and between her legs. Crain passed away in the intensive care unit just hours after her mother desperately begged doctors to intervene.</p>
<p>While Roe V. Wade and reproductive rights is a common Democratic talking point, it’s not the only threat to women following Trump’s reelection.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.aol.com/news/body-choice-women-report-rise-171545142.html?guccounter=1&amp;guce_referrer=aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbS8&amp;guce_referrer_sig=AQAAAIhnF_3LpV56S9Ox9kt8XSGBo-y-2jlppuxczOqlQrXfYah08_bEf31_zDcrFwtqvAyRlSIa2LU0AoA-fF76YWnZr3TGJRDXlqPjTIk2h9FOuVljaR6kxaaezilInSChhY-EbptgmRGzCxiJKPBYyZVWFj_yCfBHB_eibwWBIwaK" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AOL reports</a> that many women have faced men writing “your body, my choice” on their <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@camichurro_123/video/7434335152005729579" target="_blank" rel="noopener">social media posts</a>, as an inverse to the feminist slogan “my body, my choice”.</p>
<p>The phrase has <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@emazzaspams/video/7434203599216856351" target="_blank" rel="noopener">quickly gained traction</a> on TikTok, where women have expressed feeling that their bodies no longer belong to them in the wake of the presidential election results.</p>
<p>We have effectively built a pathway for these types of men to feel comfortable saying these things without consequence, setting up the next generations to lose.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not only an issue with our presidential votes, but local ones too.</p>
<p>California has successfully voted against <a href="https://calmatters.org/california-voter-guide-2024/propositions/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">three more ‘liberal’ propositions</a> on their state ballot, restricting the state as a whole.</p>
<p>Proposition 6, which aimed to end involuntary labor by incarcerated individuals, was rejected with 54.8% voting ‘No’. Proposition 32, which proposed raising the minimum wage to $17/hr and $18/hr starting January 1, 2025, was also rejected with 51.8% voting ‘No’. Proposition 33, which would repeal the ban on local rent control, was rejected with 61.4% voting ‘No’.</p>
<p>Voting based only on present convenience, or on what’s right in front of us at the moment, sacrifices the needs and rights of those who come after us.</p>
<p>Take climate change, for example. During Trump’s first term, he withdrew the United States from the Paris Climate Agreement, citing the “unfair economic burden” it placed on American workers. The decision was <a href="https://www.npr.org/2020/11/03/930312701/u-s-officially-leaving-paris-climate-agreement" target="_blank" rel="noopener">highly protested</a> by various scientists and science advocacy groups.</p>
<p>In other administrations, such as Bill Clinton&#8217;s, acts that were designed to reduce the negative effects of climate change <a href="https://unfccc.int/kyoto_protocol" target="_blank" rel="noopener">had trouble getting backed</a> by the Senate.</p>
<p>The Republican Senate majority shows just how powerful short-sighted voting can be. The Senate has the power to confirm judicial nominees of the Supreme Court, making it all too easy for Trump to <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/dispatches/donald-trumps-supreme-court-majority-could-easily-rule-through-2045" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reshape the courts for decades</a>.</p>
<p>With Senate support, he could urge for current justices to retire, and replace them with much younger candidates that share his views, locking us all in for <a href="https://www.google.com/amp/s/amp.cnn.com/cnn/2024/11/08/politics/trump-grasps-unprecedented-power-supreme-court-immunity" target="_blank" rel="noopener">that lifetime appointment</a>.</p>
<p>“I expect Alito to announce his retirement in the spring of 2025…I hear some folks say that Thomas won’t retire,” wrote Ed Whelan, a conservative lawyer, in <a href="https://www.nationalreview.com/bench-memos/perpetuating-a-strong-conservative-majority-on-the-supreme-court/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an essay</a> on the National Review&#8217;s Bench Memos blog, “But it would be foolish of him to risk repeating Ruth Bader Ginsburg’s mistake… So expect him to decide to retire in the spring of 2026.”</p>
<p>Rights we may take for granted, like what happened with <a href="https://www.npr.org/2022/06/24/1102305878/supreme-court-abortion-roe-v-wade-decision-overturn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reproductive choice</a>, could continue being steadily rolled back as the Supreme Court sees fit.</p>
<p>Future generations of Americans will live in a country shaped by today’s selfish votes, where affordable housing and essential freedoms are out of reach.</p>
<p>To move forward, we must vote with empathy, valuing long-term stability over short-term satisfaction.</p>
<p>It’s time to prioritize the common good over fleeting anger because by focusing on winning in the moment, we’re setting the nation up to lose the future.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/opinion-voter-spite-is-jeopardizing-our-future/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fresno State&#8217;s production of &#8220;Red Velvet&#8221; shares untold Black history</title>
		<link>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/red-velvet-preview/</link>
					<comments>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/red-velvet-preview/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[By Oscar Alexander, Reporter]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 21:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Theatre]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fresno State Theatre]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Red Velvet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stage play]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/red-velvet-preview/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Lolita Chakrabarti’s “Red Velvet” is set to make its Fresno theatre premiere tonight as Fresno State’s University Theatre’s third show of the 2024-25 mainstage season. Directed by Fresno State theater professor Brad Myers, the production is set against the backdrop of 19th century London. The play follows the true story of Ira Aldridge, the first...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lolita Chakrabarti’s “Red Velvet” is set to make its Fresno theatre premiere tonight as Fresno State’s University Theatre’s third show of the 2024-25 mainstage season.</p>
<p>Directed by Fresno State theater professor Brad Myers, the production is set against the backdrop of 19th century London. The play follows the true story of Ira Aldridge, the first Black man to play Shakespeare’s highly-revered Othello on a major English stage.</p>
<p>The story sees Aldridge in his later years, with flashbacks that showcase the racism, oppression and triumphs he faced throughout his life and career.</p>
<p>“This was right after slavery was abolished [in London],” lead actor Jimmy Haynie told The Collegian. “It was extremely controversial and scandalous to have a Black man perform on stage during this time and previously, it had only been done in blackface by Edmund Kean.”</p>
<figure id="attachment_111652" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-111652" style="width: 742px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-111652" src="https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Red-Velvet-3-min-600x400.jpg" alt="" width="742" height="495" srcset="https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Red-Velvet-3-min-600x400.jpg 600w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Red-Velvet-3-min-1200x800.jpg 1200w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Red-Velvet-3-min-768x512.jpg 768w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Red-Velvet-3-min-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Red-Velvet-3-min-300x200.jpg 300w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Red-Velvet-3-min.jpg 2001w" sizes="(max-width: 742px) 100vw, 742px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-111652" class="wp-caption-text">Jimmy Haynie (pictured far right) and fellow cast members during rehearsal for &#8220;Red Velvet.&#8221; (Courtesy of Miguel Gastelum)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Haynie said he was excited to portray such an important historical figure but was skeptical about the play’s authenticity before auditioning.</p>
<p>“I was unsure how to feel about a black story being told from a non black perspective,” Haynie said. “But early on in the process, I think what made me most excited was being able to tell this important story. I think people like him deserve to be heard about and learned about, because he, and we know this from so many wonderful black people in history, a lot of our history is forgotten.”</p>
<p>The show marks Myers’ final directorial feat after a 42-year-long career.</p>
<p>“When I first was looking for a show for my swan song I read an awful lot of plays, more plays than usual, because I was looking for something very particular,” Myers told The Collegian. “I wanted a piece of theater that I would be really passionate about, and I wanted a show that was really good for our theater arts majors…I finally came across Red Velvet, and that was a very exciting find.”</p>
<p>Myers has previously directed Fresno State productions of “Much Ado About Nothing,” “The Private Life of the Master Race” and <a href="https://cah.fresnostate.edu/theatrearts/faculty-staff/faculty/myers.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">many more.</a></p>
<p>With “Red Velvet,” he hopes to deliver a fresh take on a relatively unknown story.</p>
<p>“I think that this play can be more impactful, has the potential to be more impactful,” Myers said. “It doesn&#8217;t just feel like just an old history lesson. The issues are certainly of racism and misogyny. Ira Aldridge was also an American. He was an American-born actor, and so there&#8217;s xenophobia in the play, because they&#8217;re mortified. There&#8217;s some voices in the play that really think that they need to preserve the traditions, the English traditions of Shakespeare, and that that does not include having a black man play a fellow, or an American stepping onto the stage in a Shakespearean play.”</p>
<figure id="attachment_111650" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-111650" style="width: 868px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class=" wp-image-111650" src="https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Red-Velvet-2-min-600x400.jpg" alt="" width="868" height="579" srcset="https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Red-Velvet-2-min-600x400.jpg 600w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Red-Velvet-2-min-1200x800.jpg 1200w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Red-Velvet-2-min-768x512.jpg 768w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Red-Velvet-2-min-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Red-Velvet-2-min-300x200.jpg 300w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Red-Velvet-2-min.jpg 2001w" sizes="(max-width: 868px) 100vw, 868px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-111650" class="wp-caption-text">Jimmy Haynie (pictured left) and fellow cast members during rehearsal for &#8220;Red Velvet.&#8221; (Courtesy of Miguel Gastelum)</figcaption></figure>
<p>“I&#8217;m satisfied,” Myers said. “I don&#8217;t know that I&#8217;ve really had an end in vision, if that makes sense. I haven&#8217;t had an end in sight. It&#8217;s just do the best I can with every show I take on. You know, do the best I can given where I am at in my own artistic development, and I feel that that’s happened.”</p>
<p>Myers says the goal for this production is to inspire people to not give up on their dreams, even when it seems like the odds are stacked against them.</p>
<p>“I think his story is inspirational,” Myers said. “And for a lot of people today who encounter obstacles because of who they are, for whatever reason, the color of their skin, their gender, their sexual identity, anything like that. Ira Aldrich fought through that adversity, and ultimately his whole life was a real triumph over that adversity.”</p>
<p>Haynie also agrees that Aldridge’s story is one that will inspire.</p>
<p>“I think people who will take the most away from it are those who are driven and…are working towards those goals,” Haynie said. “It’s very telling of the time nowadays…we still struggle with inclusion and diversity in in our profession.”</p>
<p>Performances will run Dec. 6-7, 10-14, and will start at 7:30 p.m. at the John W. Wright Theatre on the Fresno State campus. An additional performance will be held Dec. 8 at 2 p.m.</p>
<p>Doors open 30 minutes before curtain and latecomers will not be allowed in, according to the press release.</p>
<p>Tickets are $20 for adults, $18 for Fresno State faculty, staff, alumni and military and $10 for all students.</p>
<p>The box office is open 12-3 p.m. on Tuesday-Thursday, and one hour before each performance.</p>
<p>Parking is free for shows on Friday through Sunday night. For shows on Tuesday through Thursday night, parking permits are required and can be purchased at dispensers in parking lots on campus for $5.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/red-velvet-preview/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fresno State women&#8217;s basketball runs away with victory over UC Merced</title>
		<link>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/fresno-state-womens-basketball-runs-away-with-victory-over-uc-merced/</link>
					<comments>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/fresno-state-womens-basketball-runs-away-with-victory-over-uc-merced/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[By Vincent Ordonio, Reporter]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 06:35:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Women's Basketball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jaime white]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mia Jacobs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://fscollegian.com/?p=111640</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Despite being down two starters, the Fresno State women’s basketball team (7-3) came away with a win against the University of California, Merced 83-60 on Thursday, Dec. 5, at the Save Mart Center. Senior guard Saga Ukkonen joined sophomore guard Taija Sta. Maria (lower leg injury) on the injury list. Head Coach Jaime White said...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite being down two starters, the Fresno State women’s basketball team (7-3) came away with a win against the University of California, Merced 83-60 on Thursday, Dec. 5, at the Save Mart Center.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Senior guard Saga Ukkonen joined sophomore guard Taija Sta. Maria (lower leg injury) on the injury list. Head Coach Jaime White said she’s managing an injury from the game </span><a href="https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/jacobs-shines-as-fresno-state-womens-basketball-bounces-back-with-ot-win-over-ut-martin/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">against the University of Tennessee at Martin</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> last week and her return is imminent. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We need her rested and she’s day-to-day right now,” White said. “I think she’s doing really well, so we’re hoping to have her back soon.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Freshman guard Danae Powell took over point guard duties and impressed her coach on both ends of the court in Ukkonen’s place.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I think [Danae] runs the offense really well, sees the open person; you saw those baseline passes, I thought she did a good job there,” White said. “She’s also tough defensively and is able to defend in a lot of different ways, so we’re really excited to see her get some opportunities.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Powell recorded a season-high five assists along with seven points in her first start of the season. Junior forward Mia Jacobs also pitched in as she recorded her seventh double-double of the season with 18 points and 11 rebounds to go along with her three steals. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jacobs logged a new season-high of four 3-pointers against the Bobcats which she thought was important as it allows for herself and others to score in the paint.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Keep [shooting] and knowing the next one’s going to go in is really important,” Jacobs said. “Then drawing the defense out after you hit a couple [3-pointers], then that’s when you start to drive or get pull ups and find teammates.”</span></p>
<p><b>What happened </b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jacobs led the team in the first quarter as she scored the team’s first seven points, but the Bobcats kept themselves in the game after a slow start defensively for the Bulldogs. The ‘Dogs closed out the quarter with a 17-11 lead after a well-balanced offensive game plan- driving to the paint and kicking it out for 3-pointers. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To open the second quarter, the Bulldogs went on a 12-5 run fueled by their 3-point shooting as Powell and junior guard drained one 3-pointer each, which opened up opportunities in the paint.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But the Bobcats were still in the game heading into halftime as they were also making their 3-pointers, with the Bulldogs leading 38-27.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At the half, the Bulldogs played strong defense as they forced the Bobcats to eight turnovers while recording three blocks and five steals. They also held the Bobcats to 9-of-32 (28.1%) shooting from the field and did a good job at closing out on 3-point shooters as the Bobcats only attempted eight 3-pointers and made three of them. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the third quarter, the Bulldogs gave the Bobcats a different look on defense as they pressed up full court, which resulted in four turnovers and three steals for the ‘Dogs. The Bulldogs also carried their hot shooting into the third quarter as they went 4-of-8 from the 3-point line, contributing to their 63-44 lead as the quarter came to a close.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the final quarter, the Bulldogs kept the Bobcats at a distance as they maintained their lead throughout the quarter in route to winning the game 83-60.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After finding success with a zone defense early in the season, White felt it wasn’t as effective this game, which led to the team pressing up full court in the third quarter. The change helped the team in a rhythm to pull away with the win.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite the considerable deficit, the Bobcats had their way from beyond the arc, shooting 9-of-19 from three. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I don’t think our zone was as good tonight, but I liked our press; our press really got us back into it,” White said. “In the second half, we allowed too many threes, and credit to their team. I told their coach, &#8216;That&#8217;s the best somebody’s played against our zone,’ so we’re going to have to work on some things.”</span></p>
<p><b>What’s next</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Bulldogs get a brief break before heading to the Galen Center next Tuesday to take on the No. 6 Trojans of the University of Southern California (USC). </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It will be another tough test for Fresno State with USC possessing a pair of first team Associated Press preseason </span><a href="https://apnews.com/article/college-basketball-ap-allamerica-team-447452800081a79ebcf587c16e19f35c"><span style="font-weight: 400;">All-Americans</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in JuJu Watkins and Kiki Iriafen.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/fresno-state-womens-basketball-runs-away-with-victory-over-uc-merced/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fresno State drops conference opener to No. 24 San Diego State</title>
		<link>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/fresno-state-drops-conference-opener-to-no-24-san-diego-state/</link>
					<comments>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/fresno-state-drops-conference-opener-to-no-24-san-diego-state/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[By Vincent Ordonio, Reporter]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 20:48:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Editors' picks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Men's Basketball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magoon Gwath]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mykell Robinson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san diego state]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://fscollegian.com/?p=111631</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Fresno State men’s basketball team (3-5) opened Mountain West play with an 84-62 loss to No. 24 San Diego State on Wednesday, Dec. 4, extending its losing streak to three. Junior forward Mykell Robinson led the Bulldogs as he recorded his second double-double of the year with a season-high in points (20) and rebounds...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Fresno State men’s basketball team (3-5) opened Mountain West play with an 84-62 loss to </span><a href="https://apnews.com/hub/ap-top-25-college-basketball-poll"><span style="font-weight: 400;">No. 24</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> San Diego State on Wednesday, Dec. 4, extending its losing streak to three.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Junior forward Mykell Robinson led the Bulldogs as he recorded his second double-double of the year with a season-high in points (20) and rebounds (10). This came as junior guard Amar Augillard and freshman forward Elijah Price entered foul trouble early in the game and eventually fouled out.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Even with a good start to the game on offense and defense, the Bulldogs could not maintain their momentum as the Aztecs’ size and length proved to be too much. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">50 of the Aztecs’ 84 points came from the paint as they used their size to their advantage. The Bulldogs also gave up 13 offensive rebounds, which allowed for 19 second chance points for the Aztecs. In comparison, the Aztecs only conceded 26 of the Bulldogs’ 62 points in the paint while also recording six blocks.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Head Coach Vance Walberg said even though the Aztecs’ size may have affected the team’s ability to score in the paint, it&#8217;s a matter of getting accustomed to it.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I’m not going to say [the Aztecs’ size] didn’t [have an effect], it’s nice to have a 7-footer and a 6-foot-10 guy down there,” Walberg said. “But I think it’s more of just settling down a little bit more and getting used to it.”</span></p>
<p><b>What happened</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The first quarter of the game started off with high defensive intensity as both teams struggled to score, with the Bulldogs looking to trap players on defense early.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eventually, three minutes into the game, the Bulldogs would be first on the scoreboard after a 3-pointer from Robinson off a drive and kick from junior forward Alex Crawford. This was followed by an Aztec layup two minutes later to bring the score 2-3 early in the first quarter. </span></p>
<figure id="attachment_111638" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-111638" style="width: 758px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class=" wp-image-111638" src="https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/MG_2886-600x400.jpg" alt="" width="758" height="505" srcset="https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/MG_2886-600x400.jpg 600w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/MG_2886-1200x800.jpg 1200w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/MG_2886-768x512.jpg 768w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/MG_2886-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/MG_2886-300x200.jpg 300w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/MG_2886.jpg 2001w" sizes="(max-width: 758px) 100vw, 758px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-111638" class="wp-caption-text">Forward Alex Crawford jumps to block shot against San Diego State at the Save Mart Center on Dec. 5. (<a href="https://fscollegian.com/staff_profile/chase-gauthier/">Chase Gauthier</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As the quarter trudged on, the defense showed to be too aggressive as Augillard entered foul trouble when he earned his third foul of the quarter.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a result, Augillard, who is </span><a href="https://www.espn.com/mens-college-basketball/team/stats/_/id/278/table/game/sort/avgPoints/dir/desc"><span style="font-weight: 400;">the team&#8217;s leading scorer</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, had to sit out the rest of the first half. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With Augillard out for the remainder of the first quarter, Walberg thought the team did a good job in his absence. After a slow start to the game, he thought the team needed to find another way to win.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“When Amar came out early, I think we were down five, I thought we did a really good job,” Walberg said. “Amar is one of those guys where you hope he hits those shots, and if he hits those shots, he’s going to really help you. If he isn’t, then we got to find another way to win.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To close the first quarter, after a battle on defense, the Bulldogs finished on a 7-2 run sparked by Crawford to bring the score to 29-24 with the Aztecs in the lead.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Heading into halftime, both teams were shooting poorly from the field. The Bulldogs were 7-of-33 (21.2%) from the field while shooting 2-of-13 (15.4%) from 3-point range. Meanwhile, the Aztecs were slightly better as they were 11-of-30 (36.7%) from the field and 4-9 (44.4%) from three.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To open the second half, Price joined Augillard in foul trouble with three as the Aztecs slowly pulled away with the lead. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As the quarter went on, the Bulldogs were not showing that defensive intensity seen in the first quarter as players were slow to close out, communicate and rebound. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Robinson said after strong defense in the first half, they were lacking in the second half which he said is something they need to work on.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We played pretty good defense throughout the first half, and then in the second half, when we’re not on the side with our coaches on the bench, we kind of get slacking. So that’s something we definitely need to pick up,” Robinson said. </span></p>
<figure id="attachment_111634" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-111634" style="width: 600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-111634" src="https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/MG_3104-600x400.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="400" srcset="https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/MG_3104-600x400.jpg 600w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/MG_3104-1200x800.jpg 1200w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/MG_3104-768x512.jpg 768w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/MG_3104-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/MG_3104-300x200.jpg 300w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/MG_3104.jpg 2001w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-111634" class="wp-caption-text">Mykell Robinson speaks to the media after the game. (<a href="https://fscollegian.com/staff_profile/chase-gauthier/">Chase Gauthier</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To close the game, the Bulldogs tried to fight back but the Aztecs’ proved to be too much for the ‘Dogs and they lost 84-62.</span></p>
<p><b>What’s next</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Bulldogs look to bounce back against Santa Clara University at the Leavey Center on Saturday, Dec. 7 at 4 p.m.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/fresno-state-drops-conference-opener-to-no-24-san-diego-state/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fresno State hires Matt Entz as its next head coach</title>
		<link>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/fresno-state-hires-matt-entz-to-be-its-next-head-coach/</link>
					<comments>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/fresno-state-hires-matt-entz-to-be-its-next-head-coach/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[By Al Scott, Sports Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 17:54:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Football]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Sports Story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[football]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Matt Entz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tim skipper]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://fscollegian.com/?p=111615</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fresno State football team is hiring former North Dakota State Head Coach and University of Southern California (USC) linebackers coach Matt Entz to be the 23rd head coach in program history. &#8220;Entz is a proven winner with a championship pedigree, consistently leading his teams to success on the field. He is a leader of people...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fresno State football team is hiring </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">former North Dakota State Head Coach and University of Southern California (USC) linebackers coach Matt Entz to be the 23rd head coach in program history.</span></p>
<div class='infographicwidget'><div class='center'></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">A new era of Bulldog Football<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/203c.png" alt="‼" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>Welcome to the Valley, <a href="https://twitter.com/Coach_Entz?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Coach_Entz</a>  <a href="https://t.co/waOTql6WcO">pic.twitter.com/waOTql6WcO</a></p>
<p>— Fresno State Football (@FresnoStateFB) <a href="https://twitter.com/FresnoStateFB/status/1864469411320766931?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 5, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div></div><div class='clear'></div>
<p>&#8220;Entz is a proven winner with a championship pedigree, consistently leading his teams to success on the field. He is a leader of people who values growth both on and off the field,&#8221; said Director of Athletics Garrett Klassy. &#8220;Matt and his family embody the core values of integrity, grit, hard work, and selflessness that define what it means to be a Bulldog. We are confident that they will make meaningful contributions to our University, city, and the entire Valley.&#8221;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He now takes over for Fresno State interim head coach Tim Skipper who went 6-6 during the 2024 regular season. Since 2017, the Bulldogs have had four 10-win seasons.</span></p>
<p>Klassy added, &#8220;I want to extend my deepest gratitude to Tim Skipper for his unwavering dedication and leadership during a pivotal time for our football program. His commitment to our student-athletes and the university exemplifies the true spirit of Bulldog tenacity and resilience. Tim&#8217;s efforts have been instrumental in maintaining the high standards of excellence we uphold at Fresno State.&#8221;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Entz went 60-11, with a 15-3 playoff record as the lead man for the Bison from 2019 to 2023. This includes two NCAA Division I Football Championship Subdivision (FCS) National Titles in 2019 and 2021. Both years, he was named the American Football Coaches Association (AFCA) Coach of the Year. </span></p>
<p>The 2019 season was impressive in particular. He became the first Division I head football coach to go 16-0 in his first full season at the helm, defeating James Madison 28-20 to win the 2019 Division I FCS national Championship. The Bison that season became the first modern-era college football team in any division to finish a season 16-0, joining the 1894 Yale Bulldogs as the only 16-0 teams in college football history.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He spent the previous five seasons as the team’s defensive coordinator. On Dec. 10, 2023, Entz got hired at USC. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In his only season, the Trojans jumped from No. 119 to 70 in </span><a href="https://www.ncaa.com/stats/football/fbs/current/team/22/p2"><span style="font-weight: 400;">total defense</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The <a href="https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/mikey-keene-among-several-dogs-entering-transfer-portal/">transfer portal</a> opens today so Entz will have to make quick work to revamp the roster for the 2025 season.</span></p>
<p>There will be press conference tomorrow for Entz tomorrow at 10 a.m.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/fresno-state-hires-matt-entz-to-be-its-next-head-coach/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fresno State welcomes No. 24 Aztecs to town for Mountain West Conference opener</title>
		<link>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/fresno-state-welcomes-no-24-aztecs-to-town-for-mountain-west-conference-opener/</link>
					<comments>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/fresno-state-welcomes-no-24-aztecs-to-town-for-mountain-west-conference-opener/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[By Al Scott, Sports Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 16:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Men's Basketball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Douglas Jr.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san diego state]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vance walberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zaon Collins]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://fscollegian.com/?p=111613</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Fresno State men’s basketball team welcomes No. 24 San Diego State into the Save Mart Center today, to open up Mountain West Conference play. The Aztecs are a premiere program in college basketball, having made the NCAA tournament the last four seasons and 11 of the last 14 years. They also made the NCAA...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Fresno State men’s basketball team welcomes </span><a href="https://www.espn.com/mens-college-basketball/rankings"><span style="font-weight: 400;">No. 24</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> San Diego State into the Save Mart Center today, to open up Mountain West Conference play.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Aztecs are a premiere program in college basketball, having made the NCAA tournament the last four seasons and 11 of the last 14 years. They also made the NCAA title game during the 2022-23 season. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">They will be playing at Fresno State as a ranked team for the ninth time in program history. It is also the 15th time the Bulldogs will host a nationally-ranked team.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Aztecs are 4-2 on the season, with losses to then No. 3 Gonzaga and unranked Oregon. They already have a pair of ranked wins though, defeating No. 21 Creighton and No. 6 Houston last week during the Players Era Festival in Las Vegas. </span></p>
<div class='infographicwidget'><div class='center'></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">WHAT A FINISH TO INCREASE THE AZTEC LEAD  <a href="https://t.co/Tlbgq55iuB">pic.twitter.com/Tlbgq55iuB</a></p>
<p>— NCAA March Madness (@MarchMadnessMBB) <a href="https://twitter.com/MarchMadnessMBB/status/1863045512426917953?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 1, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div></div><div class='clear'></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite a tough non-conference schedule, the Aztecs are allowing just 64.7 points per game (PPG). </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Head Coach Vance Walberg lauded Aztecs Head Coach Brian Dutcher for his team’s efforts on stopping opposing teams from scoring. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“They have the culture to develop. They know defense wins,” Walberg said. “When you have that kind of a culture, what happens to the referees is that you get away with a little bit more too.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Bulldogs are 31-26 all-time at home against SDSU but winning has come hard as of late. Since 2019, the Aztecs have won ten-straight games against Fresno State.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Walberg emphasized that protecting the basketball and grabbing rebounds would be paramount if they want to compete with SDSU. </span></p>
<p><b>Key players to watch</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Aztecs have a trio of players scoring in double figures this season: BJ Davis, Nick Boyd and Miles Byrd. All three are threats to score from anywhere on the floor. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Davis in particular has been lights out from deep, shooting 50% from beyond the arc early in the season. Boyd leads the team with 3.33 assists per game.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Freshman seven-footer Magoon Gwath leads the </span><a href="https://www.ncaa.com/stats/basketball-men/d1/current/individual/138"><span style="font-weight: 400;">NCAA</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> with four blocks per game, for what is a very good Aztec defense. Offensively, he has the ability to score inside and out. </span></p>
<div class='infographicwidget'><div class='center'></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="tl">Magoon Gwath  | 7&#8217;0 F | San Diego State <a href="https://t.co/oPLnSpzFUa">pic.twitter.com/oPLnSpzFUa</a></p>
<p>— So Elite Basketball (@SoeliteBBall) <a href="https://twitter.com/SoeliteBBall/status/1862246221685170492?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 28, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div></div><div class='clear'></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“He’s one of those types of players that, we&#8217;ll have to concede something,” Walberg said. “I would rather see him outside shooting threes than inside kicking us on the boards. So, it&#8217;s a give and take in how we play it.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a team, the Aztecs are shooting 38.5 percent from three. They’re also outplaying teams in transition and forcing turnovers at a high rate (12.3 per game). </span></p>
<p><b>The newest Bulldog star</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sophomore Zaon Collins is averaging 15 ppg, 5.2 rebounds per game and 3.4 assists per game. The former top recruit has found a new home with the Bulldogs. He says that Walberg’s play style allows him to be both a scorer and a facilitator. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“He gives us the ability to play freely, and we just go out there and we just have fun,” Collins said. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Walberg says that if they are going to be successful, he needs a little more though from his ‘top notch point guard.’ </span></p>
<figure id="attachment_108888" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-108888" style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-108888" src="https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Zaon-Collins-1-400x600.jpg" alt="" width="400" height="600" srcset="https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Zaon-Collins-1-400x600.jpg 400w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Zaon-Collins-1-800x1200.jpg 800w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Zaon-Collins-1-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Zaon-Collins-1-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Zaon-Collins-1-200x300.jpg 200w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Zaon-Collins-1.jpg 1334w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-108888" class="wp-caption-text">Transfer point guard Zaon Collins during the first half against Sacramento State, making his Bulldog debut. (Alexis Bruno/The Collegian)</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“He&#8217;s got to concentrate a little bit better, more on defense to help us,” Walberg said. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite being 6-foot-1, Collins has the speed and active hands to make an impact defensively like what Walberg is looking for. </span></p>
<p><b>Injury bug</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Walberg announced that forward David Douglas Jr. would be out for four to six weeks with a knee injury that he suffered </span><a href="https://fscollegian.com/2024/11/fresno-state-goes-on-14-0-run-in-comeback-win-over-long-beach-state/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">last week</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Forward Pierre Geneste Jr. is still out with a finger injury but is meeting with doctors on Thursday. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While known for using a press defense, Walberg has rarely used it this season due to injuries stacking up. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“When you look down at your paper and you go, I got two guys on the bench. One&#8217;s at 60%, one&#8217;s at 70% and then, the foul trouble is what really scares me,” Walberg said. “You need depth right now, I&#8217;m playing some guys way too many minutes as it is.”</span></p>
<p><b>Upcoming games</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tip-off for Wednesday’s game with the Aztecs is at 7:30 p.m. and will be broadcasted on Fox Sports 1. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Bulldogs hit the road again this weekend, playing at Santa Clara on Saturday, Dec. 7. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/fresno-state-welcomes-no-24-aztecs-to-town-for-mountain-west-conference-opener/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fresno&#8217;s newest park offers a taste of nature</title>
		<link>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/fresnos-newest-park-offers-a-taste-of-nature/</link>
					<comments>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/fresnos-newest-park-offers-a-taste-of-nature/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[By Isaac Marquez, Reporter]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ball Ranch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nature trail]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://fscollegian.com/?p=111607</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Down the scenic Old Friant Road lies a brand new park filled with activities and beautiful views. Ball Ranch is a new park that opened on Nov. 12, and is around 350 acres on the San Joaquin River Parkway. It is open seven days a week and the hours of operation change depending on the...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Down the scenic Old Friant Road lies a brand new park filled with activities and beautiful views.</p>
<p><a href="https://riverparkway.org/places/ball-ranch/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ball Ranch</a> is a new park that opened on Nov. 12, and is around 350 acres on the San Joaquin River Parkway. It is open seven days a week and the hours of operation change depending on the season. Admission and parking is also free for everyone.</p>
<p>The park is home to a large pond where people can fish for bass, catfish or panfish. There is a bait shop near the entrance where guests can purchase fishing supplies as well as snacks and beverages.</p>
<figure id="attachment_111610" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-111610" style="width: 719px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-111610" src="https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Ball-Ranch-2-600x400.jpg" alt="" width="719" height="479" srcset="https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Ball-Ranch-2-600x400.jpg 600w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Ball-Ranch-2-1200x800.jpg 1200w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Ball-Ranch-2-768x512.jpg 768w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Ball-Ranch-2-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Ball-Ranch-2-300x200.jpg 300w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Ball-Ranch-2.jpg 2001w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 719px) 100vw, 719px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-111610" class="wp-caption-text">Ball Ranch&#8217;s fishing pond. (Isaac Marquez/The Collegian)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Stunning views riddle the park while opportunities to watch wildlife are common. Guests will also find massive and scenic trails for hiking, biking and even horseback riding.</p>
<p>Jill Jones is a retired real estate broker who now rides her three horses daily. She recently went to Ball Ranch for the first time and went horseback riding there.</p>
<p>“I will recommend it to others,” Jones said. “If you stay on the designed trail, it&#8217;s not as fun as wandering off into the unknown. We did find dried river beds that had beautiful sand and are much safer for our horses.”</p>
<p>Jones added that her time there was wonderful and that she will be returning to continue her exploration.</p>
<figure id="attachment_111611" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-111611" style="width: 734px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-111611" src="https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Ball-Ranch-3-600x400.jpg" alt="" width="734" height="489" srcset="https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Ball-Ranch-3-600x400.jpg 600w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Ball-Ranch-3-1200x800.jpg 1200w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Ball-Ranch-3-768x512.jpg 768w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Ball-Ranch-3-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Ball-Ranch-3-300x200.jpg 300w, https://fscollegian.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Ball-Ranch-3.jpg 2001w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 734px) 100vw, 734px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-111611" class="wp-caption-text">Jill Jones taking her horse for a ride at Ball Ranch. (Isaac Marquez/The Collegian)</figcaption></figure>
<p>The park is funded through the <a href="https://sjrc.ca.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">San Joaquin River Conservancy</a> which is a state-funded organization according to Sarah Parkes, assistant director at <a href="https://riverparkway.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">River Parkway Trust</a>. The Trust oversees around 5,000 acres and preserves the San Joaquin River areas in Northern Fresno.</p>
<p>She added that in the 80s, Ball Ranch was slated to be turned into high-end housing and a golf course, but was stopped by Mary Savala, Clary Creager and Peg Smith, the <a href="https://riverparkway.org/what-we-do/historical-timeline/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">group of women who began the San Joaquin River Committee</a>. This committee would later turn into the River Parkway Trust.</p>
<p>“So Ball Ranch is at the heart of our history and so it is really exciting now that it&#8217;s open again for the public to enjoy,” Parkes said.</p>
<p>The park has plans to add more benches and tables in the near future, while permanent restrooms are long-term goals.</p>
<p>The park is also connected to <a href="https://riverparkway.org/places/sumner-peck-ranch/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sumner Peck Ranch</a>, which is a 78-acre property that has seasonal fruit pickings and orchards to admire.</p>
<p>Ball Ranch will hold its official grand opening on Dec. 13 where all are welcome to attend.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/fresnos-newest-park-offers-a-taste-of-nature/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mikey Keene among several &#8216;Dogs entering transfer portal</title>
		<link>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/mikey-keene-among-several-dogs-entering-transfer-portal/</link>
					<comments>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/mikey-keene-among-several-dogs-entering-transfer-portal/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[By Al Scott, Sports Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 20:29:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Football]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gavriel Lightfoot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mikey Keene]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Phoenix Jackson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transfer portal]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://fscollegian.com/?p=111602</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When the Fresno State football team plays its bowl game later this month, the roster will look a little bit different. Quarterback Mikey Keene announced this morning that he will be entering the transfer portal, which will officially open tomorrow, Dec. 4.  In two seasons at Fresno State, Keene completed 68.7% of his passes for...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When the Fresno State football team plays its bowl game later this month, the roster will look a little bit different.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Quarterback </span><a href="https://www.espn.com/college-football/player/_/id/4597499/mikey-keene"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mikey Keene</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> announced </span><a href="https://x.com/Mikey_Keene/status/1864026071127236984"><span style="font-weight: 400;">this morning</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that he will be entering the transfer portal, which will officially open tomorrow, Dec. 4. </span></p>
<div class='infographicwidget'><div class='center'></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="zxx"><a href="https://t.co/wfFGe0gAJj">pic.twitter.com/wfFGe0gAJj</a></p>
<p>— Mikey Keene (@Mikey_Keene) <a href="https://twitter.com/Mikey_Keene/status/1864026071127236984?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 3, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div></div><div class='clear'></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In two seasons at Fresno State, Keene completed 68.7% of his passes for 5,868 yards and 42 touchdowns. He also threw 21 interceptions. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Backup </span><a href="https://www.espn.com/college-football/player/_/id/4832830/joshua-wood"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Joshua Wood</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is expected to start in his place during the bowl game. Wood has five rushing touchdowns this season, but he has only attempted five passes this season. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Keene is the latest in a slew of players to announce their intent to transfer since the ‘Dogs loss to UCLA on Saturday. </span></p>
<div class='infographicwidget'><div class='center'></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="zxx"><a href="https://t.co/YmUd6p5Q4o">pic.twitter.com/YmUd6p5Q4o</a></p>
<p>— alzillion hamilton (@alzillionhamil1) <a href="https://twitter.com/alzillionhamil1/status/1863978713563709826?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 3, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div></div><div class='clear'></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Linebacker </span><a href="https://www.espn.com/college-football/player/_/id/4875604/phoenix-jackson"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Phoenix Jackson</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, defensive linemen </span><a href="https://www.espn.com/college-football/player/_/id/4912252/gavriel-lightfoot"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gavriel Lightfoot</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><a href="https://www.espn.com/college-football/player/_/id/4900355/julius-gandy"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Julius Gandy</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, cornerbacks </span><a href="https://www.espn.com/college-football/player/_/id/4690606/alzillion-hamilton"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Al&#8217;zillion Hamilton</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><a href="https://www.espn.com/college-football/player/_/id/4432277/justin-houston"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Justin Houston</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, wide receiver </span><a href="https://www.espn.com/college-football/player/_/id/5151404/antoine-sullivan"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Antoine Sullivan</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and tight end </span><a href="https://www.espn.com/college-football/player/_/id/4875608/kamron-beachem"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kameron Beachem</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> have also expressed their intent to enter the portal once it officially opens. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jackson, Lightfoot and Hamilton were all key starters for the Bulldogs this season. Them leaving will open up playing time for others throughout the roster for both the bowl game and next season. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/mikey-keene-among-several-dogs-entering-transfer-portal/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dogs in the NFL: Week 13</title>
		<link>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/dogs-in-the-nfl-week-13/</link>
					<comments>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/dogs-in-the-nfl-week-13/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[By Finnley Pendergast, Reporter]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 17:54:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Football]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Former Bulldogs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daron Bland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Davante Adams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[derek carr]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://fscollegian.com/?p=111594</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Daron Bland makes his return to Dallas This past Thursday, Bland recorded nine total tackles with a pass defended in the 27-20 home win over the New York Giants on Thanksgiving.  The former Bulldog defensive back started the season on the injured reserve due to a foot injury caused in a preseason practice.  The All-Pro...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><b>Daron Bland makes his return to Dallas</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This past Thursday, Bland recorded nine total tackles with a pass defended in the 27-20 home win over the New York Giants on Thanksgiving. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The former Bulldog defensive back started the season on the injured reserve due to a foot injury caused in a preseason practice. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The All-Pro made his first appearance of the season in the Cowboys’ loss to the Commanders back in week 12. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bland’s return can help the Cowboys secondary that has struggled to come up with interceptions.</span></p>
<p>The corner was also busy handing out turkeys this past week.</p>
<div class='infographicwidget'><div class='center'></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Forgot to post this earlier, but Cowboys CB DaRon Bland and his charity, Bland Beyond Boundaries, partnered with the Wilkinson Center in Dallas for a Thanksgiving turkey basket drive to help support local families in need. Bland also wrote a check donation for the center. <a href="https://t.co/BjdFpu3nUF">pic.twitter.com/BjdFpu3nUF</a></p>
<p>— Joseph Hoyt (@JoeJHoyt) <a href="https://twitter.com/JoeJHoyt/status/1862602655995949524?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 29, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div></div><div class='clear'></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The (5-7) Cowboys will next face the (4-8) Cincinnati Bengals on Monday Night Football on Dec. 9.</span></p>
<p><b>Davante leads Jets receivers in loss</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite a solid showing from Adams, the New York Jets lost to the Seattle Seahawks 26-21 at home.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The former Bulldog finished the day with 5 receptions for 66 yards and a receiving touchdown. He did most of his damage in the first half, catching just one ball in the final thirty minutes of action. </span></p>
<div class='infographicwidget'><div class='center'></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Vintage Rodgers to Adams for six.</p>
<p>: <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SEAvsNYJ?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#SEAvsNYJ</a> on FOX<br />
: <a href="https://t.co/waVpO909ge">https://t.co/waVpO909ge</a> <a href="https://t.co/X7fLS2K3oN">pic.twitter.com/X7fLS2K3oN</a></p>
<p>— NFL (@NFL) <a href="https://twitter.com/NFL/status/1863290004296069264?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 1, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div></div><div class='clear'></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Jets looked ready coming off their bye week as they took an early two score lead in the first quarter. The offense got cold, not scoring at all in the second half. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">During the Jets bye week, there was lots of talk about the future of quarterback Aaron Rodgers as well as where Davante may end up after this season. As of now, the duo will continue to suit up for the Jets.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The (3-9) Jets will play on the road next against the (5-7) Miami Dolphins on Sunday, Dec. 8.</span></p>
<p><b>Carr and the Saints lose their eighth game of the season</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The New Orleans Saints fell to the Los Angeles Rams at home on Sunday, losing 21-14.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Carr went 24-of-37, throwing for 184 yards and one passing touchdown. His lone touchdown went for 28 yards to receiver Marquez Valdes-Scantling in the fourth quarter.</span></p>
<div class='infographicwidget'><div class='center'></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">TOUCHDOWN MVS!</p>
<p>His 4th TD in 4 games with the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Saints?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Saints</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/LARvsNO?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#LARvsNO</a> | : FOX <a href="https://t.co/mZCh8nIMJh">pic.twitter.com/mZCh8nIMJh</a></p>
<p>— New Orleans Saints (@Saints) <a href="https://twitter.com/Saints/status/1863363115263705179?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 1, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div></div><div class='clear'></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The loss makes the road to the playoffs quite difficult as they now sit at 4-8 on the year and in third place of the National Football Conference (NFC) South. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Saints will look to rebound next week on the road against the (2-10) New York Giants on Sunday, Dec. 8.</span></p>
<p><b>Other ‘Dogs in the NFL</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Defensive end Aaron Mosby ended the game with two tackles and a tackle for loss in the Packers’ win over the Dolphins on Thanksgiving. Mosby was evaluated for a concussion in the win but was a full participant in Green Bay’s latest practice. The (9-3) Packers will be on the road next when they take on the (11-1) Detroit Lions on Thursday Night Football on Dec. 5.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Safety Evan Williams continued his solid play with seven tackles in the Packers’ Thanksgiving win.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Saints running back Jordan Mims was inactive in the loss to the Rams. He did not play due to the coach&#8217;s decision. With backup running back Jamaal Williams returning from his injury, it may be hard for Mims to find any action going forward.</span></p>
<div class='infographicwidget'><div class='center'></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">just a couple of Bulldogs in the NFL <a href="https://twitter.com/jmims23?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@jmims23</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/lilronnie_20?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@lilronnie_20</a><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/BulldogBornBulldogBred?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#BulldogBornBulldogBred</a> <a href="https://t.co/vfibbJ72n2">pic.twitter.com/vfibbJ72n2</a></p>
<p>— Fresno State Football (@FresnoStateFB) <a href="https://twitter.com/FresnoStateFB/status/1863383727570878701?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 2, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div></div><div class='clear'></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Linebacker Mykal Walker recovered a fumble in the Washington Commanders’ win over the Tennessee Titans on Sunday. The (8-5) Commanders are on bye next week with their next game being against the (4-8) New Orleans Saints on Sunday, Dec. 15.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://fscollegian.com/2024/12/dogs-in-the-nfl-week-13/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
